The adventure of a lifetime!
Ivanhoe is a history, adventure, tv movie film directed by Douglas Camfield.
Ivanhoe, a worthy and noble knight, the champion of justice returns to England after the holy wars, and finds England under the
reign of Prince John and his henchmen and finds himself being involved in the power-struggle for the throne of England.
Wilfred of Ivanhoe, played by Anthony Andrews.
Isaac of York, played by James Mason.
Brian de Bois-Guilbert, played by Sam Neill.
Cedric, played by Michael Hordern.
King Richard, played by Julian Glover.
Prince John, played by Ronald Pickup.
Ivanhoe is a 1982 historical romance television film directed by
Douglas Camfield, with a screenplay written by John Gay.
An adaptation of Walter Scott's 1819 novel of the same name, it stars Anthony Andrews in the title role and depicts the noble knight
Ivanhoe returning home from the Third Crusade and becoming involved in a power struggle for the throne of England.
Brian de Bois-Guilbert is treated more ambiguously
than in most versions of the story.
He develops some genuine affection for Rebecca of York towards the end, and although he could easily have won the fight against the wounded and
weakened Wilfred of Ivanhoe, Brian de Bois-Guilbert lowers his sword and allows himself to be killed, thus saving Rebecca's life.
The film explores themes of knight, miniseries,
jousting, middle ages (476-1453), 12th century.